Guide to the James Jesse Strang Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section B: Personal Papers
  - 154. JOHN E. PAGE. MS. overture to debate, dated Voree, Aug 26, 1849. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 155. INCREASE VAN DEUSEN. ALS dated [New York ca. Dec 21, 1849] to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 156. GEORGE J. ADAMS [?] Unsigned MS address to "King James." 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 157. ANSON W. PRINDLE. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 14, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 158. GILBERT WATSON. ALS, dated Voree, Jan 7, 1850, to James J. Strang at Washington [forwarded to Baltimore]. 3 p. foolscap; and attached leaf. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 159. LOUISA [LOUISA SANGER?]. ALS, dated Ottawa, [I11.,] Apr 18, 185[0?], to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 160. LOUISA I. ADAMS. ALS, [Beaver Island? 1850?] to George J. Adams. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Section C: The Church Archives
  - 161. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Record of the Chatham Branch at Litchfield, Medina Co., Ohio, 1843-45. Includes minutes of proceedings before the organization of the Strangite church. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 162. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Record of organization of Chicago Branch, May 10, 1846, with list of members and resolutions passed. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 163. JOHN C. BENNETT. MS. of a portion of the ritual of the Order of Illuminati. 2 p. 8vo. [ca. Jul 6, 1846]. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 164. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated [Burlington, Wis.,] [Aug 15, 1846], to James J. Strang at Boston. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 165. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Burlington [Wis.,] Aug 18, 1846, to James J. Strang at Boston. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 166. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Record of the organization of the Philadelphia Branch, Sep 2-6, 1846. With list of 33 members. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 167. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Minutes of conference at Voree [Oct 1846]. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 168. [COLLINS PEMBERTON]. MS. proceedings of trial before the High Council at Voree, Oct 25, 1846. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 169. NELSON R. & LEVENNA JOHNSON. MS. depositions, dated Voree, Nov 3, 1846. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 170. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Resolutions of the Boston branch, Feb 1, 1847. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 171. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. MS. resolution signed James J. Strang, Patriarch, B. G. Wright, Steward, and Anson W. Prindle, Asst., Jun 10, 1848, at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 172. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. Resolution adopted Sep 8 [9?], 1848, signed James J. Strang, Patriarch, Ben- gamin G. Wright, Steward, Anson W. Prindle, Asst. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 173. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. MS. order adopted Sep 23, 1848, signed James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 174. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. Report of the committee on clothing, signed Gilbert Watson, B. G. Wright, John Porter, Voree, Sep 23, 1848. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 175. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. MS. report of the "Committee on Accountabilities, dated Sep 23, 1848, and signed by James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 176. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. MS. minutes of the Order of Enoch dated "City of Enoch," Dec 26, 1849, signed A. C. B. Fields, O. R. Hill, John H. Brown, Rubin Field [and "Since that time":] David Brown, Julius Hickox, William H. Tripp, and Albert Field. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 177. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH. MS. depositions by Finley Page, Spaulding Deloss, Andrew J. Parris, Asa C. Field, Joseph Ketchum, and Walter Ostrander, in the suit of Archer vs. Strang as trustee of the Order of Enoch. [ca. 1850.] 4 p. 8vo, 10 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 178. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH [?] MS. list of 29 names headed by that of Strang, in each case followed by a series of unitary digits. 2 p. 8vo. in pencil. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 179. ASSOCIATED ORDER OF ENOCH[?] MS. report of the building committee concerning receipts and expenditures for the year Oct 6, 1847 to Oct 5, 1848. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 180. [WILLIAM SMITH.] Trial of William Smith before the First Presidency on charges of adultery. [ca. Apr 23, 1847]. 1 p. folio. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 181. [WILLIAM SMITH. Trial for Adultery.] Testimony by Sarah Ellsworth taken by James J. Strang, Apr 23, 1847. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 182. [WILLIAM SMITH. Trial for Adultery.] "Copy of the questions put to B. C. Ellsworth by John C. Gaylord and Wm. Smith." [ca. Apr 23, 1847]. Answers by Ellsworth not included. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 183. JOHN W. CRANE. ALS, dated Voree, Sep 26, 1847, to James J. Strang. Financial report on the Church by Crane as Bishop, evidently to be reported to the October conference, 1847. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 184. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. Subscription lists for the building of the Temple and the Tower of Strength on the Hill of Promise at Voree. [n.d. 1847?] 1 8vo and 1 foolscap page pasted together. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 185. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite).] Ground plans [at Voree?]. 2 diagrams. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 186. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite).] Proceedings in the New York branch [ca. Sep 1849]. 5 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 187. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite).] MS. minutes of discourses at the Church conference at Beaver Island, Jul 2-3, 1850, including remarks by George J. Adams and James J. Strang. 7 p. foolscap [in part in pencil]. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 188. [CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS (Strangite)]. MS. testimony of witnesses. 234 signatures, of men and women, including some of the best-known names associated with the Strangite Church. 8 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Section D: General Correspondence
  - 189. SAMUEL ABBOTT. ALS dated Makinac May 2, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - l90. G. P. ACKERT. ALS dated Black River, N.Y., Mar 28, 1850, to James J. Strang at Voree, Wis. l p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 191. G. P. ACKERT. ALS dated Clayton Post Office at French Creek Jeff. Co. N.Y. to James J. Strang, ca. Apr, 1850. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 192. G. P. ACKERT. ALS dated Clayton [N.Y.], Sep 24, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 193. G. P. ACKERT. ALS dated Clayton [N.Y.], Jul 29, 1851, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 194. DANIEL M. ADAMS. ALS, n.d., n.p. [1846?] to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 195. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS "To the Saints Scattered abroad in all the World," intended for publication in the Voree Herald, dated Lewisburgh, Ohio, Jul 6, 1846, addressed to James J. Strang at Voree, Wis. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 196. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Dayton, Ohio, Aug 3, [1846], to James J. Strang at Kirtland, Ohio. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 197. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Dayton, Ohio, Aug 3, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree, Wis. 6 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 198. GEORGE J. ADAMS. MS account with Adams, E. J. Moore, and Eli Steele, dated 1848, sums due for sundry manual services performed. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 199. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Wilmington, Delaware, Nov 1, 1849, to James J. Strang at Philadelphia. His discourses at Wilmington. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 200. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated New York, Dec 3, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 201. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS dated Washington, D. C., to George J. Adams, Nov 29, 1849. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 202. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated New York, Dec 5, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 203. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Boston, Mass., Dec 11, 1849, to James J. Strang. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 204. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Boston, Mass., Dec 22, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 205. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Boston, Mass., Jan 15, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 206. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Boston, Mass., Jan 17, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 207. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Baltimore [i.e., Boston, Mass.]. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 208. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Boston, Mass., Jan 31, 1850, to James J. Strang. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 209. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated [Boston, Mass.,] Thursday Jan 31 [i.e., Thursday, Feb 1], 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 210. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Baltimore, Md., [Feb] 18, 1850, to James J. Strang. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 211. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated Baltimore, Md., Mar 1, [1850], to James J. Strang at Philadelphia. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 212. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS dated "on Steam Boat near Mackinaw 3 p M" [Aug 1, 1850] to James J. Strang [at Beaver Island]. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 213. GEORGE J. ADAMS. ALS to his wife Louisa I. H. Adams at Zion [Beaver Island], dated "on Board the Steamer Michigan" August 1 [1850]. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 214. HAZEN ALDRICH. ALS dated Willoughby, Lake County, Ohio, Apr [14?], 1846, to Strang at Burlington, Wis. 6 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 215. M. M. ALDRICH. Contemporary copy of letter [apparently in the hand of Elvira Field], dated Beaver Island, Nov 23, 1849 to Samuel Graham. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 216. S. ALEXANDER. ALS to James J. Strang dated Buffalo, Nov 22, 1854, enclosing bills for various articles of machinery. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 217. S. ALEXANDER. ALS dated Chicago, Apr 6, 1855, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 218. NAOMI ALVORD. ALS dated Far West, Caldwell Co., [Missouri], Apr 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 219. C. W. APPLETON, ALS dated New Bedford, Mass., Dec 17, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 220. MARY APPLETON. ALS dated Philadelphia, Nov 22, 1849, to George J. Adams at Baltimore. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 221. LOIS AUSTIN. ALS dated Beaver Island, Nov 20, 1849, to Samuel Graham at Boston, and endorsed without signature by Graham to Strang. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 222. ELISHA BARTON. ALS dated West Jersey, Stark County, Ill., Nov 11, 1850, to Strang. 1 p. 8vo. 0 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 223. GEORGE H. BENEDICT. ALS dated Southport, Wis., May 15, 1846, to Strang at Burlington. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 224. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Mar 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree, Wis. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 225. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Mar [25?], 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 226. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Mar 29, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 227. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Mar 31, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 228. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Apr 6, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 229. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Apr 14, 1846, to Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 230. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Steamer Michigan [Cin- cinnati, OH], Apr [18?], 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 231. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Plymouth, Mass., May 27, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 232. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Plymouth, Mass., Jun 12, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 233. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS dated Voree, Wis., Jul 29, 1846, to General James Arlington Bennet. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 234. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Burlington, Wis., Aug 11, 1846, to James J. Strang at New York City. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 235. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Burlington, Wis., Aug 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at Boston. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 236. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Plymouth, Mass., Dec 13, 1849, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 237. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, n.d., n.p. [obviously written at Plymouth, Mass., in Jan, 1850] to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 238. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Plymouth, Mass., May 29, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 239. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Plymouth, Mass., Nov 25, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 240. JOHN C. BENNETT. ALS, dated Plymouth, Mass., Mar 31, 1851, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 241. SAMUEL BENNETT. ALS, dated Williamsburgh, Long Island, N.Y., Dec 11, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 242. SAMUEL BENNETT. ALS, dated Williamsburgh, N.Y., Mar 12, 1850, to James J. Strang at Philadelphia. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 243. SILAS BENNETT. ALS, dated Belvidere, Ill., Apr 23, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 244. JAMES BLAKESLEE. ALS, dated Batavia, Kane Co., Ill., Oct 4, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 245. H. BOARDMAN. ALS, dated Grand Travers Bay Mich, Sep 16, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. 8vo.James Jesse Strang Collection (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 246. ALFRED BONNEY. ALS, dated Conneaut, Crawford Co., Pa., Apr 11, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 247. DANIEL F. BOTSFORD, NANCY BOTSFORD, & JOHN ALSTON. MS deposition undated [ca. Jan 1847?]. Chicago? 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 248. DANIEL F. BOTSFORD. ALS, dated [Chicago, Ill.,] Jan 9, 1847, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 249. DANIEL F. BOTSFORD. ALS, dated [Chicago, Ill.,] Jan 12, 1847, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 250. DANIEL BOTSFORD. ALS, dated Chicago, Jan 29, [1847], to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 251. DANIEL F. BOTSFORD. ALS, dated Chicago, May 20, 1847, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 252. SAMUEL BOUTIKER. ALS, dated New Trenton, Franklin Co., Ia., May 10, 1847, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 253. THOMAS W. BRAIDWOOD. Harper's Ferry, Virginia, 3 ALS dated Dec 3, 10, and 16, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. each 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 254. THOMAS W. BRAIDWOOD. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Jan 3, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 255. THOMAS W. BRAIDWOOD. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Jan 9, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 256. THOMAS W. BRAIDWOOD. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Jan 24, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 257. LESTER BROOKS. ALS, [dated Laporte, Ohio, May 8, 1846], to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 258. LESTER BROOKS. ALS, dated [Ravenna, O.,] Mar 14, 1847, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 259. LESTER BROOKS. ALS, dated Buffalo, [N.Y.?] Aug 17, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 260. LESTER BROOKS. ALS, dated Buffalo, N.Y., Mar 20, 1850, to James J. Strang at Boston. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 261. HIRAM P. BROWN. ALS, dated Porter, [ ], Jan 19, 1850, to James J. Strang at Washington. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 262. HIRAM P. BROWN. ALS, dated Fulton, Wis., Feb 16, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 263. HIRAM P. BROWN. ALS, dated Fulton, Wis., May 21, 1850, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 264. HIRAM P. BROWN. ALS, dated Oswego, N.Y., Aug 29, 1850, to Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 265. HIRAM P. BROWN. ALS. dated Koshkonony, [Wis.?], Aug 6, 1851, to Mrs. Mary Strang, Elgin, Ill. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 266. GEORGE BROWNSON. ALS, dated Chicago, Mar 27, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 267. GEORGE BROWNSON, ALS, dated Jefferson, N.Y., Jul 29, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 268. GEORGE BROWNSON [with additions by FRANK COOPER]. ALS, dated Landoff, Grafton County, N.H., Nov 15, 1849. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 269. GEORGE BROWNSON. ALS, dated Portland, Me., Dec 27, 1849, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 270. GEORGE BROWNSON. ALS, dated Theresa, N.Y., May 27, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 271. GEORGE BROWNSON. ALS, dated Mackinac, [Mich.,] Jul 19, 1851, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 272. JULIA BULKLEY. ALS, dated Brownshelm, [i.e., Birmingham?], Lorain Co., Ohio, Aug 19, 1850, to James J. Strang at "Big Beaver Island". 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 273. HUNT F. BUTLER. ALS, dated St. Charles, [Ill.?], Apr 27, 1847, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 274. ZIMERI [?] BUTTERFIELD. ALS, dated Chicago, Aug 8, 1851, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 275. THOMAS CAHOON. ALS, dated Cuyahoga Falls, Ohio, May 7, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 276. A. B. CALKINS. ALS dated French Creek, Jefferson [Co.], N.Y., Feb 25, 185[0?], to James J. Strang at Washington, D. C. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 277. JAMES CANNEY. ALS, dated New York, Jun 16, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 278. JAMES CANNEY. ALS, dated New York, Nov 18, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 279. ALONZO CHESSEMAN. ALS, dated [n.p.] Jul 28, 1851, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 280. GEORGE H. CHEREVOY. ALS, dated New York, Jan 17, 1850, to James J. Strang at Washington. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 281. DENNIS CHIDESTER. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 6, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 282. DENNIS CHIDESTER. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 16, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 283. DENNIS CHIDESTER. ALS, dated Voree, Mar 28, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 284. DENNIS CHIDESTER. ALS, dated Mackinac, [Mich.,] Nov 12, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 285. MRS. LURENA CLARK. ALS, dated Cass, Ill., Jun 26, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 286. ANNA COLE. ALS, dated [Beaver Island?], Apr 3, 1851, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 287. JOHN COLE. ALS, dated Elizabeth, Ill., Jan 10, 1850 to James J. Strang at Washington. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 288. JOHN S. COMSTOCK. ALS, without date, endorsement upon an ALS by FREDERIC FREEMAN to James J. Strang, dated Barre, Jackson Co., Michigan, Mar 3, 1849. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 289. JOHN S. COMSTOCK. ALS, dated Springport, [Mich.?], Apr 22, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 290. JOHN S. COMSTOCK. ALS, Dated Springport, [Mich.?], Jul 1, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 291. JOHN S. COMSTOCK. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 28, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. 4 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 292. D. COOLEY. ALS, dated Washington, Macomb Co., Mich, May 23, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 293. M. COPELAND. ALS, dated Norvoo, Franklin Co., Alabama, Apr 3, 1849, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 294. A. COWLES. ALS, (n.p., n.d.], to James J. Strang, with endorsement by Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 295. SARAH T. CRAWFORD. ALS, dated Brownvill, Me., Nov 30, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 296. ASA CURTIS. ALS, dated Armada, [Mich.?], Apr 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 297. THEODORE CURTIS. ALS, dated St. Louis, Mo., Mar 14, 1847, to John Greenhow at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 298. MARY DEMARY. ALS, [n.p., n.d. ca. 1849 or 1850], to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 299. JAMES DENSMORE. ALS, dated [Jul 24, 1846?], Oshkosh, Wis., to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 300. A. DERROUGH. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Jul 4, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 301. A. DERROUGH. ALS, dated Cincinnati, Ohio, Aug 20, 1846, to James J. Strang at New York City. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 302. WILLIAM R. DIXON. ALS, dated Quincy, Ill., Jun 15, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 303. JOEL DRAPER. ALS, dated Northingwillemburg, N.Y., Mar 14, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 304. GEORGE W. DUNCAN. ALS, dated [Bowling Green, (Indiana?)], Mar 31, 1850, to James J. Strang at Voree. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 305. CHARLES DURKEE. ALS, dated Washington, D. C., Dec 25, 1849, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8 vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 306. CHARLES DURKEE. ALS, dated [Washington, D. C.,] Jan 31, 1856 [1854?] to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 307. D. W. ELMORE. ALS, dated Asylum, Elgin, Ill., May 21, 1846, to James J. Strange. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 308. GEORGE ENGLAND. ALS, dated Ilion, N.Y., June 15, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 309. SAMUEL G. FLAGG. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Feb 4, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 310. NATHAN FOSTER. ALS, dated Kosknony, [Wis.?], Nov. 26, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 311. JOSEPH GEORGE. ALS, dated New Bedford, Mass., Jan 15, 1850, to George J. Adams at Boston. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 312. D. S. GIBBS. ALS, dated [n.p.] May 25, 1846, to [James J. Strang?] 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 313. JACOB GIBSON. ALS, dated Philadelphia, Apr. 10, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 314. JACOB GIBSON. ALS, dated Philelphia, Jun 25, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2p 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 315. M. M. GILLETT. ALS, dated Mackinaw, [Mich.], Aug 6, 1851 to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 316. J. D. GOSSICK. ALS, dated Racine, [Wis.], Mar 23, 1853, to James J. Strange. 1p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 317. A. J. GRAHAM. ALS, dated Albion, [Mich.,] Jan 22, 1850, to James J. Strang at Washington. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 318. MARIETTA GRAHAM. ALS, dated Waukegan, [Ill.?], Aug 11, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 319. MARIETTA GRAHAM. ALS, dated Washington Island, [Mich.?], Oct 18, 1849, to [James J. Strang?] 2 p. 8vo. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 320. SAMUEL GRAHAM. ALS, dated Leroy, Mich., Jan 15, 1848, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 321. SAMUEL GRAHAM. ALS, dated Bath Mills, [Mich.,] Jan 23, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 322. SAMUEL GRAHAM. ALS, dated Bath Mills, [Mich.,] Feb 6, 1849, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 1, Folder 40)